Mss.Ms.Coll.113
American Philosophical Society
- Series VIII. Certificates and Awards, 0.5 linear feet
  - Membership Certificate, 1954 May; 2.0 items; Washington Academy of Sciences (Washington, D.C.). (Box 49)
  - Commendation for White Sands Missile Range Aerobee Program, 1963 December; undated; 2.0 items; United States. Dept. of Defense. (Box 49)
  - Bowie Medal Awarded to Herbert Friedman 1981 - Correspondence and Program, 8.0 items; American Geophysical Union. (Box 49)
  - Wolf Foundation Prize - Newspaper Clippings, Programs and Correspondence, 1987; 54.0 items; Wolf Foundation Prizes. (Box 49)
  - Distinguished Civilian Service Awards, 1980; undated; 3.0 items; United States. Dept. of Defense.; United States. Navy. (Oversize 1)
  - Official Commendations for Outstanding Performance, 1971; 1973; 1976; 1977; 1978; 5.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Oversize 1)
  - Research Publication Award, 1970 February; 1.0 item; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Oversize 1)
- Series IX. Personal, 0.25 linear feet
  The personal material contained in Series IX includes passports, biographical and curriculum vitae material, as well as material related to Dr. Friedman’s retirement from the Navy Research Laboratory. Also included is obituary and memorial material, including material relating the dedication of the Herbert Friedman Room at the Navy Research Laboratory.
  - Biographical Notes and Sketches, undated; 5.0 items (Box 50)
    This folder contains various drafts of biographical sketches from various publishers, including Who's Who in America and American Men and Women of Science.
  - Clippings, 1960; 1967; 7.0 items (Box 50)
  - Curriculum Vitae - Drafts and Career Highlights, Folder 1, undated; 9.0 items (Box 50)
  - Curriculum Vitae - Drafts and Career Highlights, undated; 2.0 items (Box 50)
  - Edward O. Hulburt Materials, 1955-1982; 21.0 items (Box 50)
    This folder includes Herbert Friedman's materials and correspondence that nominated Edward O. Hulburt for the Nationa Academy of Sciences' John Adam Fleming Award and his condolences upon learning of Mrs. Hulburt's passing.
  - Family Tree - Herbert Friedman, undated; 11.0 items (Box 50)
    This folder contains an impressive and clearly drawn family tree of the Friedman family, going back to 1737.
  - Dedication of the Herbert Friedman Room at Naval Research Laboratory, 2000; 6.0 items (Box 50)
    This folder contains programs of memorials and services which remember Dr. Friedman and his outstanding contributions to science.
  - Guestbook from NRL Symposium "Space Science - Past and Prologue" in Honor of Herbert Friedman, 1976 May 24; 1.0 item; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 57)
  - Guestbook on the Occasion of Herbert Friedman's Retirement from the Naval Research Laboratory, 1980 March 11; 1.0 item; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 57)
  - Handwritten Speech By Dr. Friedman within Notebook Entitled "Career", undated; 1.0 item (Oversize 3)
    This notebook seems to contain a long speech written by Dr. Friedman in his own hand.
  - International Certificates of Vaccination - Herbert Friedman, 1960-1978; 2.0 items (Box 50)
  - Personal Writings and Birthday Celebrations, 1991; undated; 6.0 items
    This folder contains a couple occasional poems by Dr. Friedman, as well as a flyer for his 75th birthday celebration.
  - Obituaries and Memorials Honoring Herbert Friedman, 2000-2001; 10.0 items (Box 50)
  - Passports of Herbert Friedman, 1967; 1977; undated.; 3.0 items (Box 50)
  - Publications List, 1964; 1.0 item (Box 50)
    This documents lists Herbert Friedman's pulbications from 1939 to 1964.
  - Quotations Collection, undated; 12.0 items (Box 50)
    This folder contains some great quotations taken down in Dr. Friedman's own hand or by letter type.
  - Security Clearances for Herbert Friedman, 1967-1970; 11.0 items (Box 50)
  - Yearly Planner, 1996; 1.0 item (Box 50)
- Series X. Printed Materials, 0.75 linear feet
  Series X, the printed materials series, consists of published works and reprints authored mainly by others, but also including work by Dr. Friedman himself. NASA manuals regarding shuttle payload development feature prominently.
  - 75th Anniversary Awards for Innovation - Celebrating 75 Years of the Naval Research Laboratory 1923-1998, 1.0 item; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 50)
  - Manuscript for Book entitled "Herbert Friedman - Pioneer in X-ray Astronomy", undated; 1.0 item (Oversize 4)
  - Astronomers - Biographies Collected By Herbert Friedman, 1983; undated; 5.0 items (Box 50)
    This folder contains biographies of astronomers which Dr. Friedman collected.
  - Beethover String Quartet 16, Great Fugue, Opus 133, undated; 1.0 item (Box 50)
  - Board on International Organizations and Programs, 1980 December; 1.0 items; National Research Council (U.S.) (Box 50)
  - Annual Report, 1987; 1.0 item; Commonwealth Fund.. (Box 50)
  - Current Biography, Vol 24, Number 8, September 1963 - Entry on Herbert Friedman, 1963 September; 1.0 item; H.W. Wilson Company. (Box 50)
  - The E.O. Hulburt Center for Space Research at the U.S. Naval Research Laboratory, 1963 February; 1.0 item; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 50)
    This small pamphlet describes the establishment of the E.O. Hulburt Center at the Naval Research Laboratory.
  - EOS, Transactions, Vol 62, Number 27, 1981 July 7; 1.0 item; American Geophysical Union. (Box 50)
    This issue of EOS details Dr. Friedman's award of the Bowie Medal in 1981.
  - Fiscal Year 1972, ICAS Report No.15, March 1971, 1971 March; 2.0 items; Federal Council for Science and Technology (U.S.). (Box 50)
    This report also includes, in looseleaf form, a document entitled "ICAS Review of NAS Report Status."
  - Reminiscences of 30 Years of Space Research, NRL Report 8113, 1977 August; 1.0 item; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 50)
  - International Geophysics Bulletin, Number 75, 1963 September; 1.0 item; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 50)
  - International Academy of Astronautics: The First Decade, 1970; 1.0 item; International Academy of Astronautics. (Box 50)
  - Dedication Program of the Laboratory of the Space Science Division and the E.O. Hulburt Center for Space Research, 1968 April 17; 1.0 item; E.O. Hulburt Center for Space Research. (Box 50)
  - Radioastronomy Studies of Venus and Mars, Astronautics & Aeronautics - April 1966, 1966 April; 1.0 item; Mayer, Cornell H., 1921-2005. (Box 50)
  - An Assessment of the Impact of World Data Centers on Geophysics, Report of the Committee on Data Interchange and Data Centers of the Geophysics Research Board, 1975 March; 1.0 item; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 50)
  - Membership, July 1, 1979, 1979 July 1; 1.0 item; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 50)
  - Apollo Soyuz Mission, 5-Day Report, JSC-09835, 1975 August; 1.0 item; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 51)
  - NASA Outlook for Aeronautics, Briefing Summary, 1976 March; 1.0 item; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 51)
  - NASA Outlook for Aeronautics, Study Report, N76-20063, TMX 72995, 1976 March; 1.0 item; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 51)
  - Physical Sciences Committee Report on NASA's Office of Space Science - Supporting Research & Technology and Data Research, 1976 May; 1.0 item; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 51)
  - Report on NASA Five-Year Planning, Fiscal Years 1978 Through 1982, 1976 October 12; 1.0 item; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 51)
  - Satellite Power System (SPS) Concept Development and Evaluation Program Plan July 1977-August 1980, DOE/ET-0034, 1978 February; 1.0 item; United States. Department of Energy.; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 51)
  - HEAO-A nominal scanning observation schedule, NASA Technical Memorandum, NASA TM X-73391, 1977 April; 1.0 item; Fishman, Gerald J. (Gerald Jay), 1943-; Stone, R.L.; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 51)
  - Executive Summary - NASA/ESA CV-990 Spacelab Simulation, NASA TM x-62, 457, ESA-SL-75-1, 1975 July; 1.0 item; European Space Agency.; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 51)
  - Geophysical Data Centers: Impact of Data-Intensive Programs, 1976; 1.0 item; Assembly of Mathematical and Physical Sciences (U.S.). Geophysics Research Board.; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 51)
  - Naturwissenschaft und Medizin, Number 19, 1967; 1.0 item; C.F. Boehringer & Soehne. (Box 51)
  - 45 Years of Progress, NRL 1923-1968, 1.0 item; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 51)
  - Naval Research Reviews, 1964; 1967; 1968; 1972; 4.0 items; United States. Office of Naval Research. (Box 51)
    This folder contains issues of Naval Research Reviews, specifically: (a) Vol. XVII, No.7; (b) Vol. XX, No.7; (c) Vol. XXV, No. 9. It also contains a reprint from May 1968, entitled "E.O. Hulburt Center for Space Research: A NRL Experiment."
  - New Scientist, 1967 July 27; 1.0 item; New Scientist Publications. (Box 51)
    Dr. Friedman had placed a sticky on page 191, to highlight an article on his work by Peter Stubbs. In order to preserve the paper, the sticky has been removed.
  - News Report, Vol. XVI, No. 7, 1966 August-September; 1.0 item; National Academy of Engineering.; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.); National Research Council (U.S.) (Box 51)
  - NRL Labstracts, 1964-1998; 8.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 51)
  - Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar, A Biographical Memoir, 1910-1995, Vol. 72, 1997; 1.0 items; Parker, E. N. (Eugene Newman), 1927- (Box 51)
  - Semaine d'Etude Sur Le Theme Les Noyaux Des Galeries - Leur Signification Dans L'Evolution Des Galaxies, En Radio-astronomie et en Cosmologie D'Observation, 1970 April 13-19; 1.0 item; Pontificia Accademia delle scienze. (Box 51)
  - Proceedings of Natural Sciences Symposium, 1993 June 14; 1.0 item; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 51)
    This symposium was held in honor of Dr. Jerome Karle, 1985 Nobel Laureate in Chemistry.
  - Report of the ISY Mission to Planet Earth Conference - A Planning Conference for the International Space Year, 1988 April 29-May 1; 1.0 item; Meyerson, Harvey; U.S. International Space Year Association. (Box 51)
  - Research Appointments in the E.O. Hulburt Center for Space Research, 1965 January; 1.0 item; National Science Foundation (U.S.).; United States. Office of Naval Research. (Box 51)
    This folder contains a form for an applicant to fill out, in order to apply for a research appointment at the E.O. Hulburt Center for Space Research.
  - Saturday Review, Issue of July 4, 1964, The Grandest Firework, 1964 July 4; 1.0 item; Saturday Review, Inc.. (Box 51)
  - Sounding Board, Vol. I, No. 2, 1971 January-March; 1.0 item; Aerojet-General Corporation. (Box 51)
  - Space Research in Japan 1988, Submitted to the Twenty-Seventh Meeting of the ICSU Committee on Space Research, 1988 June; 1.0 item; Nihon Gakujutsu Kaigi. KokuI UchuI KoIaku KenkyuI Renraku Iinkai. (Box 51)
  - Symposium on Geiger Counters, Program of October 27, undated; 1.0 item; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 51)
  - U.S. Naval Observatory Mission, Prepared by OP09B6C, 1970 November; 1.0 item; United States Naval Observatory. (Box 51)
  - U.S. Naval Research Laboratory, Bulletin, 1959 May 6; 1960 April 29; 2.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 51)
    These two issues of the U.S. Naval Research Laboratory Bulletin report Dr. Friedman's awards.
  - Final Report on the Science Definition Panel for Atmosphere, Magnetosphere, and Plasmas in Space, Spacelab Payload, NASA Grant NSG 7251, 1976 September; 1.0 item; Universities Space Research Association. (Box 51)
  - Zenit, 1978 January; 1.0 item; Stichting De Koepel. (Box 51)
- Series XI. Photographs, 1.5 linear feet
  Series XI contains photos and images of Dr. Friedman, as well as figures from his published works and printed slides from various lectures and presentations. While few of the photos are personal snapshots, they do include photos removed from various correspondence.
  - The Extreme Ultraviolet Solar Corona, undated; 4.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Oversize 5)
  - Puka Puka Photos, 1957 July; 1.0 folder (Box 52, Folder 1)
    This album contains large black and white photos showing Dr. Friedman's time in the Fiji Islands during a rocket experiment. Photographs of the experiment, including its launching, are also included.
  - Photos/Backup for Astronomer's Universe, undated; 1.0 folder (Box 52, Folder 2)
    This folder contains many sketches by Dr. Friedman's son, Jon, of scientists featured in the book Astronomer's Universe.
  - National Academy of Sciences, 129th Annual Meeting, 1992 April 28; 1.0 folder (Box 52, Folder 3)
    This folder contains transparencies and slides for Dr. Friedman's presentation at the 128th Annual Meeting of the National Academy of Sicences, April 28, 1992.
  - Global Technology 2000 Conference, 6.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 53)
  - Space Science Review - Correspondence, 1966; 6.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 53)
  - Blue Prints for the Book, Astronomer's Universe, undated; 88.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000; Friedman, Jon R. (Box 53)
  - Photographs and Negatives for the Book Astronomer's Universe, undated; 7.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000 (Box 53)
  - Astro Horizons at the Millenium, Figures, undated; 5.0 items (Box 53)
  - Photos, George R. Carruther's Projects, undated; 14.0 items; Carruthers, George R. (Box 53)
  - Co-Glow Radiation Detector, undated; 1.0 item (Box 53)
  - E. O. Hulburt Center - Groundbreaking Ceremony, Photos and Program, 1965 December 13; 7.0 items; E.O. Hulburt Center for Space Research.
    The program has been signed by Dr. Hulburt himself.
  - The Inconstant Sun, Images, 1980; 10.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000 (Box 53)
  - Carruther's Proposal to NASA, 1966-1968, undated; 1.0 item; Carruthers, George R. (Box 53)
    This undated photograph was included in a letter dated May 31, 1967.
  - International Geosphere Biosphere Program, undated; 14.0 items; National Research Council (U.S.)
    This folder contains transparencies for a talk given by Dr. Friedman.
  - Apollo Soyuz Project, undated; 4.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 53)
    This folder contains photographs of the Apollo Soyuz X-ray detector.
  - Photos from NRL Correspondence Dated July 31, 1950, 14.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 53)
  - Optics Division, Crystal Dosimeters, Charts, undated; 14.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 53)
  - Optics Division, Problem Number 37P07-04, Figures, 1953; 11.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 53)
  - Optics Division, Problem Number 37P08-01R, undated; 7.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 53)
  - Optics Division, Problem Number H20-01, undated; 3.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 53)
  - Report, Optical Aspect System for Rockets, 1956; 7.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 53)
    These photos had been removed from Series IV, Naval Research Laboratory.
  - Report, Scientific Experiments in IGY Satellites, 1957; 4.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 53)
  - Photos from NRL Symposium in Honor of Herbert Friedman, held at the National Academy of Sciences, 1976 May 24; 18.0 items; Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 53)
  - Near Earth Space - A Historical Perspective, Slides, undated; 11.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000 (Box 53)
  - Photographs of Herbert Friedman, Folder 1, undated; 44.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000 (Box 53)
    In addition to forty-four loose photos of Dr. Friedman, this folder also contains two envelopes: one large and one small. The large manila envelope contains photos of a Chinese delegation, with Dr. Friedman showing them around. The second smaller envelope shows Dr. Friedman's attendance at a COSPAR convention in Leningrad, 1970.
  - Photographs of Herbert Friedman, Folder 2, undated; 84.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000 (Box 53)
    This folder contains large black and white photos of Dr. Friedman at various formal functions.
  - President's Award 1964 Photos, 1964 June 22; 17.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000 (Box 53)
  - Reprints of Articles, 1955; 22.0 items; Philips Natuurkundig Laboratorium. (Box 53)
    This folder contains reprints of scientific articles in German, published by Philips Research Laboratories.
  - Thorne Enclosures, 1968; 10.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000 (Box 53)
  - Vatican Conference on Astronomy, 1970; 5.0 items (Box 53)
    This folder contains photos of Dr. Friedman and his wife, Gertrude, meeting Pope Paul VI. A small piece of realia, Dr. Friedman's name tag, made of leather, is included.
  - Scientific Photos, undated; 92.0 items (Box 54)
    This folder contains page-length photos in color or black and white of Dr. Friedman's many experiments and photographs of the sun or nebula. Some are quite breathtaking.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Some of these should be re-sleeved into more appropriate encasings.
  - Assorted Photos, Folder 1, undated; 6.0 items (Box 54)
    Among these six items are three manila envelopes. One manila envelope contains photos from an event where a Chinese delegation visited the E.O. Hulburt Center for Space Science. Another manila envelope contains Dr. Friedman's original sketches for the Hulburt Center's holiday greeting cards for 1965. The third manila envelope contains a layout plan for a space center at the University of California, Los Angeles.
  - Assorted Photos, Folder 2, undated; 48.0 items (Box 54)
    This folder contains two manila envelopes. One contains photos from the dedication ceremony of the E.O. Hulburt Center for Space Science; the other contains large portrait photos of Dr. Friedman.
  - Photos, undated; 31.0 items (Box 54)
    This folder contains photos of Dr. Friedman's many experiments, instrument readings, of Dr. Friedman himself and his colleagues.
- Series XII. Audio/Visual, 3.0 linear feet
  Series XII contains audio visual material, including VHS tapes, film reels and slides. Many relate to Dr. Friedman’s work with NASA and the Navy Research Lab, as well as the National Academy of Sciences sponsored PBS Series Space Age, which Dr. Friedman participated in.
  - The Astronomer's Universe - Book Promotion Large Placard, 1998; 1.0 item (Oversize 7)
  - Princeton University, Vanuxem Lecture Series - Large Poster for Dr. Herbert Friedman, undated; October 15-18; 1.0 item (Oversize 6)
  - Early X-Ray Astronomy, undated; 1.0 Videotape(s) (Box 64)
  - The Bounty Above, undated; 1.0 Videotape(s); American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics.; Hughes Aircraft Company. (Box 64)
  - Advancing Technology with Naval Research, PIN #:805654, undated; 1.0 Videotape(s); Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 64)
  - 75th Celebration Selections, Naval Research Laboratory, 1998; 1.0 Videotape(s); Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 64)
  - H. Friedman Exhibit, 2000; 1.0 item (Oversize 4)
    This is a CD that is attached to a large manila envelope contained in Oversize 4.
  - High Adventure with Lowell Thomas - Danger Island Show, Parts 1-2, undated; 1.0 Videotape(s); Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 64)
  - Diamond Jubilee - Focus on Space, Tape 1 of 2, 1998; 1.0 Videotape(s); Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 64)
  - Diamond Jubilee - Focus on Space, Tape 2 of 2, 1998; 1.0 Videotape(s); Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 64)
  - Diamond Jubilee - Special GRAB Presentation, 1998; 1.0 Videotape(s); Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 64)
  - Document Disks of Dr. Herbert Friedman, undated; 15.0 items (Box 66)
    These are large floppy 5.25" computer disks that contain Dr. Friedman's documents.
  - Post Flight Press Brief - NASA Channel 10 from NTN Feed, 1991 April 19; 1.0 Videotape(s); Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 65)
  - Science as Art - Dr. Friedman's 75th Birthday, 1991 June 21; 1.0 Videotape(s); Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 65)
  - Seals at San Nicks, undated; 1.0 Videotape(s); Naval Research Laboratory (U.S.). (Box 65)
  - The Nazis and the Bomb, undated; 1.0 Videotape(s) (Box 65)
  - Red Bomb, undated; 1.0 Videotape(s) (Box 65)
  - Director's Topical Seminar, Will the Soviet Space Program Survive? Speaker - R.Z. Sagdeev, 1993 July 29; 1.0 Videotape(s) (Box 65)
  - Science and Engineering Television Journal, "Observatories in Space", 1965 September; 1.0 Videotape(s) (Box 65)
    This videotape features a 1965 black and white interview with Dr. Friedman.
  - Hubble Space Telescope Slides, 1997; 1.0 folder (ca. 40 pp.) (Box 60)
  - Memorial Service for Dr. Friedman at the Cosmos Club, 2000 October 19; 1.0 Tape(s) (Box 66)
  - X-Ray Corona of the Sun - "Yohkoh" Soft X-Ray Telescope, 1991 November 11-27; 1.0 Videotape(s); Uchū Kagaku Kenkyūjo (Japan).; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 64)
  - Scientific Photos - Brown Folder, 1966; undated; 1.0 folder (ca. 40 pp.) (Box 61)
  - Scientific Photos - Gray Envelope, 1959; 41.0 items (Box 61)
  - The President's Award for Distinguished Federal Civilian Service - Dr. Herbert H. Friedman, 1964 June 22; 1.0 Film reel(s) (Box 62)
    This film reel of Dr. Friedman's award cermony is shot in 16mm color, projected at 24 frames per second, with a running time of 14 minutes.
  - Skylab and the Sun, MSFC 76-423, Copy No. 2, 1968 December; 1.0 Reel(s); United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 58)
  - Skylab and the Sun, MSFC 76-423, Copy No. 26, 1968 December; 1.0 Reel(s); United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 59)
  - Slides from Experiments and Celestial Bodies, undated (Box 63)
  - Space Age #3, 1992 October 26; 1.0 Videotape(s) (Box 65)
  - PI Clip S082b, MSFC 74-379, 1968 December; 1.0 Reel(s); United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. (Box 59)
  - Pioneering the Space Frontier - An Exciting Vision of Our Next Fifty Years in Space, 1986; 1.0 Videotape(s); United States. National Commission on Space. (Box 64)
  - WQED-Space Project "Eclipse at Danger Island", 1992 April 14; 1.0 Videotape(s) (Box 66)
  - WQED-Space Project "Samoa Natives", 1992 April 14; 1.0 Videotape(s) (Box 66)
- Series XIII. Jon Friedman Art Notebooks
  - Blocco Spirale, Schizzi e Disegni, undated; 1.0 item (Oversize 3)
  - Lehigh Sketchbook, undated; 1.0 item (Oversize 3)
  - Sketch of Albert Einstein, undated; 1.0 item (Oversize 2)
    This sketch of Albert Einstein was done most likely by Jon Friedman, Dr. Herbert Friedman's son.
  - Sketchbook, Folder 1, undated; 1.0 folder (Oversize 2)
    This sketchbook contains a letter, dated April 1, 1991, from Robert A. Kolodny to Dr. Herbert Friedman. Professor Kolodny includes a photocopy of a sketch of Hyman Siegel by Herbert Friedman during the 1930s. Hyman Siegel was Professor Kolodny's grandfather; Mr. Siegel had taught a young Herbert Friedman bar mitzvah lessons.
  - Looseleaf Prints of Scientists, undated; 20.0 items (Oversize 2)
  - Five Billion Vodka Bottles to the Moon, Sketches for Book, undated; 4.0 items (Oversize 2)
- Series XIV. Restricted Nominations and Personnel Files, undated; 6.0 folders (Box 67)
  Access to this series has been restricted.